# Todd Fischeid

address 109 S Knightsbridge Rd. Cary, NC 27513

tel 919.434.4214

email toddeischeid@gmail.com

web toddeischeid.com

#### Goal

An opportunity to contribute a blend of creativity, human factors psychology, user experience, design, and software development skills. This breadth gives me a unique skill set on a team. I naturally think in terms of novel and creative solutions to problems, and enjoy building the designs that I create. The best user experience comes from a deep understanding both of users' jobs and of the technologies used to craft that experience.

### **Experience**

### Principle UX Architect, Allscripts Healthcare, Raleigh, NC January 2012 - Present

Inventor/co-inventor on 20 patents at Allscripts.

#### **Data Visualization and Analysis**

Used R statistical software for formal analyses and visualizations using applot:

Explored Opioid data for trends and to answer questions that the client had about their opioid prescriptions.

Analyzed usage analytics and visualized using ggplot; used the results to create UI prototypes that had similar data to to real application

Conducted a study on icon preferences and I used R for the statistical analyses and final charts.

Created data visualization guidelines to be used across the company. Allscripts heavily used Power BI, and I was required to tailor the guidelines assuming that PowerBI would be the tool used.

#### Web UI Development

Created web application to document clinical risk items. I performed all roles for this product: requirements gathering, UI design, development, and ongoing maintenance/support. Uses Angular and Swift+Vapor for the Web API.

Created UI proof-of-concept applications using Angular and D3js.

# Todd Eischeid

address 109 S Knightsbridge Rd. Cary, NC 27513

tel 919.434.4214

email toddeischeid@gmail.com

web toddeischeid.com

Showed feasibility of UI designs.

Created a patient data generator in Swift that creates realistic patient records for use in UI designs and development testing.

Created the UI Starter Kit. It is a collection of NPM packages that greatly reduce the development effort needed to align with UX design guidelines. Used across the company.

#### **User Research and Testing**

Shadowed nurses in hospital settings to gather user requirements a mobile nursing application

Shadowed family physicians for a natural language processing dictation EHR feature

Interviewed third-party developers to understand their usage of Allscripts application interfaces.

Interviewed medical practice patient portal administrators to gather requirements for our portal administrative console.

On-site usability testing at multiple sites across the U.S. for a homecare mobile application.

### Human Factors Engineer, IBM Corporation, Research Triangle Park, NC May 2004 - January 2012

When mobile design first started, gained fluency in mobile application design, mobile web UI frameworks, technologies for cross-platform deployment, mobile specific usability and user interface design best practices.

Achieved IBM Master Inventor status. Inventor and/or co-inventor on 25 United States patents.

Planned and conducted usability tests with customers; presented results to software developers and project managers; worked to get improved designs into the products.

Created high fidelity design prototypes using the Dojo javascript toolkit

2008-2011: User Centered Design Lead for System x server systems management tools, including Integrated Management Module, Bootable Media Creator, UpdateXpress System Pack Installer and BladeCenter Start Now Advisor (SNA). Software architecture of SNA as well as leading the UI design.

Awarded employee excellence award for my work on SNA.

2005-2008: User Centered Design Lead for IBM BladeCenter software, including Advanced Management Module (AMM) and RSA-II web consoles.

2004-2005: User Centered Design Lead for storage system software (TotalStorage Productivity Center)

# Todd Eischeid

address 109 S Knightsbridge Rd. Cary, NC 27513

tel 919.434.4214

email toddeischeid@gmail.com

web toddeischeid.com

### Senior Human Factors Consultant, Booz | Allen | Hamilton, Hampton, VA May 2002 - May 2004

Worked with NASA Langley Research Center on cockpit display specifications for the Distributed Air/Ground Traffic Management (DAG-TM) Free Flight concept

Prototyping, user testing, and specifications for free flight navigation display and primary flight display symbology

Data management, data reduction, and statistical analyses on experimental results

Experimental design and airspace scenario development

### Database Designer/Manager, Social Science Research Center, Norfolk, VA March 2000 - May 2002

Created and managed both Microsoft Access and Borland Delphi databases used by 40 state agencies; technical support and maintained web site for the databases.

User interface design for web database application.

Gathered user requirements / feedback on interface prototypes through usability testing sessions.

Packaged and deployed databases to customers using InstallShield

### Software Consultant, NASA Langley Research Center, Hampton, VA. January 2000 - August 2001

Created software to collect and analyze human electroencephalographic (EEG) and heart rate data in real time

Used Borland Delphi to create a COM server application capable of interfacing with many programming languages.

Deployed the software solution on CD-ROM using InstallShield software.

## Todd Eischeid

address 109 S Knightsbridge Rd. Cary, NC 27513

tel 919.434.4214

email toddeischeid@gmail.com

web toddeischeid.com

### Human Factors Engineer, IBM Corporation, Santa Teresa Laboratory, San Jose, CA. Internship: June 1999 -December 1999

Task Analysis for IBM e-commerce mainframe administration application; prototyped new user interfaces using Java applets and HTML

Usability testing on IBM IMS database administration software.

Developed a preliminary DB2 UDB Web Server Application, using SQL and Net.Data macros

# Researcher, Graduate Student Researchers Program (GSRP), NASA Langley Research Center, Hampton, VA. July 1998 - July 1999

Received a renewable twelve-month federal grant to independently design and conduct psychological experiments in adaptive automation

#### Application Developer, September 1997 - July 1999

Consulted with psychology professors at three different universities

Designed custom, Windows-based computer programs in Delphi and Visual Basic for psychological experiments

# Human Factors Consultant, Virginia Modeling, Analysis, and Simulation Center (VMASC), Suffolk, VA. November 1997 - July 1998

UI for an information kiosk for the United States Atlantic Command (USACOM) Joint Training, Analysis, and Simulation Center (JTASC)

Created a Borland Delphi database application that organized, stored, and retrieved data such as images, movies, and sound clips

#### Education

Ph.D. Human Factors Psychology, 2001, Old Dominion

#### University, Norfolk, VA

Title of Dissertation: Perceptual Cues And Subjective Organization In A Virtual Information Workspace

Chairperson: Mark W. Scerbo, Ph.D.

Minor: Computer Simulation / Applications of Artificial Neural Networks

# Todd Eischeid

address 109 S Knightsbridge Rd. Cary, NC 27513

tel 919.434.4214

email toddeischeid@gmail.com

web toddeischeid.com

### M. S. Psychology, 1997, Old Dominion University, Norfolk, VA.

Title of Thesis: The Effects of Task Partitioning and Computer Skill Level on Operator Engagement and Performance in an Adaptive, Biocybernetic Environment.

Chairperson: Mark W. Scerbo, Ph.D.

1997 Thomas K. Dempsey Scholarship Award Winner - outstanding student research paper in the Human Factors field

#### B.S. Psychology, 1992, Virginia Tech, Blacksburg, VA

#### **Skills**

